MOHANRAJ M

DIGITAL MARKETING

A Digital Marketer specializing in Ad Film Making, Social Media Marketing, SEO, SEM, Paid Media, Content Marketing and Email Marketing. Have 4+ years of experience in this field, worked as a freelancer for contracts as well as full-timer in individual firms, start-ups, and ad agencies, and handled 75+ brands covering 20+ fields with industry professionals across 6 countries (India, US, UK, UAE, Canada, & Australia). Now I'm here with you to share my knowledge, practices, and experience.



ADDRESS:

Karur, Tamil Nadu, IN - 639120

EMAIL:

hi@manofmarvelous.com

MOBILE NUMBER:

+91 9487936393

SKILL

Branding

Search Engine Optimization(SEO)

Search Engine Marketing(SEM)

Social Media Marketing(SMM)

Content Marketing

Email Marketing



EDUCATION

2014-2017

Bachelor of Computer Applications

St. Joseph's College, Trichy - 620002

CERTIFICATIONS

THE COMPLETE DIGITAL MARKETING COURSE - 12 COURSES IN 1

Udemy

THE FUNDAMENTALS OF DIGITAL MARKETING

Google Digital Garage

BOI RECOGNISED CREATOR

Born on Instagram

TOOLS

WEB DESIGN

Wordpress, Elementor, WooCommerce

DIGITAL MARKETING

Google Analytics, Tag Manager, Webmaster Tools, Meta Pixel, Semrush

IMAGE, VIDEO & AUDIO EDITING

Gimp, Darktable, Inkscape, Canva, Blender, Davinci Resolve, Audacity

WORK EXPERIENCE

March 2022 - November 2022 DIGITAL MARKETING ANALYST

IPCS Global (Trichy), Tamil Nadu

- I worked as a tutor and also did digital marketing services for the organization and its clients.
- To collect and analyze clients, marketing, and web data.
- Test campaigns, analyze key metrics, and identifying opportunities to increase campaign performance.
- To train, coach, support, plan, monitor and review of the students progress from the start through to the end point assessment.
- As a digital marketing tutor, I covered the courses (Professional Diploma in Digital Marketing) the syllabus for the complete digital marketing modules (Web Design (CMS), SEO, SEM, SMM, Email Marketing, Affiliate Marketing, Instant Messaging Marketing, etc.,)

November 2020 - December 2021

DIGITAL MEDIA EXECUTIVE

WOWELSE - Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

- I worked as a tutor and also did digital marketing services for the organization and its clients.
- To collect and analyze clients, marketing, and web data.
- Test campaigns, analyze key metrics, and identifying opportunities to increase campaign performance.
- To train, coach, support, plan, monitor and review of the students progress from the start through to the end point assessment.
- As a digital marketing tutor, I covered the courses (Professional Diploma in Digital Marketing) the syllabus for the complete digital marketing modules (Web Design (CMS), SEO, SEM, SMM, Email Marketing, Affiliate Marketing, Instant Messaging Marketing, etc.,)

December 2019 - January 2020

DIGITAL MEDIA EXECUTIVE

AlterEm Media Pvt. Ltd - Tiruchirappalli, Tamil Nadu

- Conduct online marketing initiatives, such as paid ad placement, affiliate programs, sponsorship programs, email promotions and marketing campaigns on social media Web sites.
- Collect and analyze campaign and feeds reach data, using web traffic metrics such as page visits, transaction size, link popularity, click-through rates and cost-per clicks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2019 - October 2019 DIGITAL MEDIA MANAGER

Mount Giris Matric Hr. Sec School - Ayyarmalai, Tamil Nadu

- Developed unique contents to improve presence and brand awareness.
- Organized and analyzed data and marketing results.
- Coordinate live-streaming events' social media interaction and broadcast. Also creating post-production content for further use across media channels.
- Collaborate with web, multimedia, or art design staffs to create multimedia web sites that conform to brand and company visual format.
- Recommend and develop strategies for growing and leveraging our social media follower base using promotions, contents, polls, ads, surveys and referral programs.
- Conduct financial modeling for online marketing campaigns over the social media platforms.

THUMBNAILS









PROJECTS

September 2021

<u>MyShubamuhurtham - Matrimony Ad</u> TV Commercial

Worked as Writer & Director. Starring Actress Nakshathra Nagesh

February 2021

Adhakalam - Short Film

Worked as Cinematographer, Editor, DI Colorist & Sfx Supervisor.

April 2019

En Iniya Palli Paruvam - Musical Video

Worked as Concept Writer, Cinematographer, Editor, DI Colorist & Director

September 2018

<u>Death Dream : The First Suspicious Entry</u> <u>Short Film</u>

Worked as Writer, Cinematographer, Editor, DI Colorist, Vfx Supervisor, Sfx Supervisor, Director & Producer

March 2018

H20 - Short Film

Worked as Editor

August 2017

Oru Manithan Piranthan - Short Film

Worked as Editor

September 2016

Yadhartham - Short Film

Worked as Editor & Director

January 2016

<u> Iyyam Thavir - Short Film</u>

Worked as Writer, Editor & Director

LANGUAGES KNOWN

TAMIL - Native

ENGLISH = Expert

AREA OF INTEREST

- BRAND DEVELOPMENT
- BRAND CONSULTATION
- ONLINE REPUTATION MANAGEMENT
- VIDEO EDITING
- PODCASTING

HOBBIES

- WRITING
- READING BOOKS
- WATCHING MOVIES
- LISTENING MUSIC

MY LIFE PHILOSOPHY

"The most powerful person in the world is storyteller. The storyteller sets the vision, values and agenda of an entire generation that is to come."

- Steve Jobs

MY SPECIALITY

OPENSOURCE APPLICATIONS

Use, Experience & Suggest to Others

LINUX OS DISTROS

Use, Experience & Suggest to Others

BOOKS/MOVIES/SERIES

Read/Watch, Enjoy & Suggest to Others